TOM STROTHER SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Nashville, TN

573.999.6990

tstrotheriv@gmail.com

in linkedin.com/in/tomstrother/

Over the past 15 years, I've lived on tour buses and in hotel rooms, zigzagging across nearly every state in the US as a Production Director in both the entertainment and corporate industries. My passion for critical thinking and problem solving helped me to become a very successful leader and team member while executing countless events. I enjoyed working directly with clients in one-on-one settings learning about their goals and expectations, and then watched their excitement as we brought it all to life.

Coming off the road, I was able to utilize those same skills to focus on creative solutions for software development with a positive and calm mindset in any situation. I have a very diverse background in multi-media and event technology, and a strong history in team-driven project execution in any environment with constantly changing requirements.

SKILLS SUMMARY

- JAVASCRIPT
- REACT HTML
- CSS
- **BOOTSTRAP**
- REACTSTRAP
- GIT/GITHUB
- AFRAME (VR)
- CLOUDINARY

EDUCATION

Nashville Software School Full-stack Web Development Bootcamp

TECHNICAL EDUCATION

Software Developer

Nashville Software School | Apr 2020 - present

Highly focused, intensive full-time software development program learning JavaScript, React, Python, and Django

- 100% on-boarding to remote learning and work environment with emphasis on teamwork skills during group projects
- Git/GitHub for version control on individual and group projects during the application build
- Built ERDs with dbdiagram.io to represent database relationships as well as leveraged Adobe XD and Figma to create accurate wireframes

CLASS PROJECTS:

- Welcome to Nashville: Developed a single page web application that allows Nashville tourists to create a "To Do" itinerary utilizing HTML5 and CSS
- Daily Journal: Used JavaScript ES6 modules, classes, and arrow functions to create a "Daily Journal" that utilized full CRUD functionality with "Get requests" to a local API using JSON-Server file. Used array methods for filtering entries Tech used: JavaScript ES6, HTML5, CSS3, JSON-Server
- Nutshell: Created a user dashboard with a login feature to access the dashboard. The dashboard featured a Chat Feed between users, To Do list, and a News Articles section populated by an API. I was responsible for the User Chat messaging feature. Tech used: JavaScript ES6, HTML5, CSS3, JSON-Server, Postman, RESTful API

INDIVIDUAL NSS PROJECTS

MyListing360 VR App

App for real estate agents and brokerages as a response to the COVID Pandemic. During the pandemic, fewer agents and buyers are willing to visit homes in person due to various local restrictions. Agents were forced to come up with creative solutions that allowed them to show listings. MyListing360 is a great, simple solution to this problem by providing a resource for agents to build and share immersive virtual tours in just minutes using 360 images of the home.

Technology Used:

- React|S via "Create React App"
- A-Frame VR (Three.js and WebVr.js) to display images in a virtual environment
- Cloudinary for image hosting
- React Bootstrap for styling
- React Google Analytics for user data tracking
- HTML/CSS/JS

WORK EXPERIENCE

Project Manager and Director of Development

Gary Musick Productions | Sep 2018 - Apr 2020 Full-service corporate and entertainment management company.

- Managed review process for proposals and executed concurrent large-scale projects (\$15,000 to \$400,000) from concept for many established known national brands; adapted to expenses above defined budget by creatively adjusting schedule, finding production substitutions, and negotiating lower costs.
- Responsible for overseeing all US based projects including logistics for team travel, inventory management, contracting local labor and on-site direction. Work closely with venue teams to ensure appropriate electrical, hospitality, and security in place for event.
- Led all hiring and in-person training of production staff, crew, and subcontractors for our execution teams.
- Quickly resolved issues that arose before, during and after events including triaging broken equipment, schedule delays, transportation issues and cancellations, time constraints due to use of union labor, and last minute client changes.
- Built monthly and weekly schedules, including goals and specific checkpoints to ensure on time delivery and within approved budget for production team to provide greater visibility and accountability to teams due to overlapping projects. Leveraged Google Docs and Teamwork software.
- Significantly decreased proposal delivery to clients from one week down to under 48hrs by creating a custom production cost calculator with Excel.
- Coached and educated sales team on how to show industry trends, what products were being sold, and how to sell products and services more successfully. Outcome: increase in company revenue.

Director of Media

First United Methodist Church | Feb 2014 - Jun 2018

- Designed, budgeted, and contracted a \$180,000+ audio visual upgrade to modern standards in high definition. Designed and installed a live streaming system for weekly broadcast similar to a TV broadcast.
- Responsible for weekly editing of audio and video for TV rebroadcast of services.
- Re-designed and built company websites using WordPress and Adobe Creative Suite and managed social media sites.
- Recruited and led 20 volunteers to execute weekly services and events, provided ongoing training programs in audio, video and streaming, and fostered supportive and encouraging collaborative work environment.
- Spearheaded community events and developed partnerships with local business to join planning and execution committees (Trunk or Treat, Movie Nights, Leadership Conference).

Tech Founder and CEO

Live It Now (Live Streaming) | Est. Feb 2011 An event tech startup

- Built well-established referral client network and worked closely with executives and project managers to identify and execute on their vision and goals.
- Created estimates, proposals, invoices, and balanced budgets using Custom excel docs, Google Drive Docs and QuickBooks Online.
- Learned HTTP live streaming protocol standards and workflow to deliver live streaming for entertainment and corporate broadcast needs. Built single page websites with WordPress and SquareSpace to host events.
- Oversaw all management and project management of travel logistics, securing contract staff, and venue staff to successfully deliver events on time and within budget. Creatively problem solved client changes, staffing issues, equipment issues, transportation issues, etc.
- Kept up with Industry standards and redesigned equipment and delivery methods to better suit the client's needs over time based on user experience.

Tech Founder and CEO

RoundHound | Est. Feb 2015

Virtual Reality Tour tech start-up for the real estate industry

Established clients through networking, maintained professional relationships with local agents and brokers, then on-boarded clients to the system with user training and account creation.

- Conceptualized and designed innovative VR platform and contracted with a team of software developers to build out application
- Established relationships with local real estate agents and brokers to onboard to platform.
- Built estimates, proposals, invoices, and balanced budgets using Custom excel docs, Google Drive Docs and QuickBooks Online.
- Quickly fixed unplanned application downtime and managed client grievances.
- Increased revenue by developing partnerships with equipment brands and became a direct re-seller to our clients rather than outsourcing.

Production Manager

Nashville Event Lighting | Jun 2008 - Oct 2013

- Executive Production Manager and Designer responsible for the design and execution of all events including corporate product activations, local business promotions, weddings, and concerts. Provided ongoing, consistent communication to clients including all budgetary elements such as pre-production, time, crew labor, overtime, travel, equipment transportation, subcontractors and expendables.
- Successfully managed 25+ events in one weekend during CMA fest around Nashville. Average weeks had 10+ events regularly with crew of 3-10 technicians on each job.
- Developed and streamlined comprehensive weekly and daily schedules to forecast length of each task to ensure all events were supported at capacity and during high volume seasons and 100% accurate management of inventory.
- Worked closely with sales team to build team budget creating custom production cost calculator automatically generating budget numbers based on equipment selections needed.
- Developed and delivered monthly in-person training programs for all new hires on equipment and safety requirements.